Swastik Suvam Singh

Address Bhubaneswar, OR 751003

Phone +918144077473

E-mail swastikpikun@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/swastik-suvam-singh-11

GitHub swastiksuvam55 (github.com)

Self-starting and resourceful Full-stack and Blockchain developer with experience implementing front-end and back-end coding. Astute and always-learning designer of user interactions on websites and databases that are sound and easy to use. Proven problem-solver with solid grounding in data-driven applications and concepts. Communicates clearly with technical and non-technical team members and promotes drive for customer service.

Skills

C/C++, Python, JavaScript, Solidity, HTML5, CSS3 React.js, Node.js, Web3.0.js, Ethereum, Hardhat, Truffle, API, Linux, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, VS code, JIRA

Work History

2022-10 - Current

React Developer Intern

Spotmies LLP, Remote-Hyderabad

- Working as the react developer for the Cypher-b project
- Wrote documentation on cryptography in blockchain and Co-mentored other interns on blockchain and ReactJS
- Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationships.
- Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers and operating systems.
 Collaborated with project managers and development team to brainstorm newideas

2022-10 - 2022-11

Web Developer Intern

Himalaya Labs, Remote-London

- Developed websites from scratch using React, Node and other libraries for various crypto summit and events.
- Concurrently managed 3+ projects at one time.
- Worked on publishing new research report on De-fi and marketanalysis.

2021-06 - 2022-10

Content Writer

Laptopnerd.in, Bhubaneswar

- Wrote and edited high-quality content and visually impactful programs under deadline pressure with exciting, captivating and authentic approach.
- Authored over 20+ articles on Science and Technology

Education

2020-11 - 2024-06

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Engineering

International Institute of Information Technology – Bhubaneswar(IIIT-BH)

Proiects

Spotmies-Cypher-b (DApp)

- Cypher-b is SaaS application which is developed on blockchain and used for smart background verification.
- The website makes it easier for the government and companies to verify the credentials of candidates which is securely stored in a public blockchain
- I worked on the front-end part of the project, mainly designing the registration, pre-registration page and the seed phase authentication for user security.

Web 3.0 Music player (Music NFT Marketplace)

- Project created using React.js, Node.js, Solidity, ether.js, hardhat
- It's designed to give artists royalty fees on the number of albums sold
- Buyers can resell their NFT's and part money of the resell always goes to the artist
- Used Open Zeppelin smart contract ERC721 to mint tokens and Ownable to implement other functions in the contract
- Hardhat was used for local deployment

Moksha

- Project created using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap4, Tailwind CSS
- The website gives the tourists live information about the traffic in tourist's places along with pollution levels and weather forecasts
- Google Maps' API from Google cloud was used to track the live traffic in the area.

Certifications

2022-08 Blockchain, IEEE-Aug'2022

2021-10 30 Days Google Cloud Program'2021 **2022-10** Full- Stack Web development, Udemy '2022

Societies/Clubs

Placement-coordinator - Helped in the placement of students to various companies **Metaverse-IIITBH Chapter-** Working as the Web3 technical lead for the chapter